Solution-focused Web Developer with experience in web-based applications. Participated in development and implementation of web-based solutions. Assisted in development and testing of mobile and web-based applications. Supported company business objectives and strategies while gaining real-world experience. Mentored under Senior php and database administrators/Developers, learning multiple systems and efficient development techniques. Consistently recognized for dependability and multi-tasking skills. Proficient with progressive web app.

### **Work History**

## 2019-09 - **Tech-executive as a Web-developer**

2020-07

SWYCH gift cards India, Goregaon, Goregaon, Mumbai, MAHARASHTRA

- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate software errors and inefficiencies.
- Adjusted software parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features.
- Review and report logs from the server-side application interface.
- Tested programs and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Performed integration testing before launching applications.
- Collaborated with IT team and other support staff to develop new applications.
- Developed and implemented scanning component using SQL Server.

2018-04 -

#### **SEO Executive**

Freelancer

2018-10

clinic Alluremedspa, Andheri, mumbai, MAHARASHTRA

- Researched and implemented search engine optimization recommendations in accordance with development methodology.
- Collaborated with team to investigate critical SEO-related issues and provided impactful solutions.
- Recommended changes to website architecture, content and linking to improve SEO positions for target keywords.
- Maintained knowledge of current market trends and algorithm updates of top search engines.
- Utilized search engine optimization and emphasized importance of link building.
- · Provided detailed reporting and analyses on client website demographics and statistics using Google Analytics.

2020-07 -

Current

self, mumbai, MAHARASHTRA

- Developed and hosted the news portal using php , Mysql.
- Developed frontend and backend for the clint
- Identified prospect needs and developed appropriate responses along with information on suitable products and services.
- Consulted with hosting providers specialists to establish new business partnerships through exploratory and informative meetings focused on value and benefits of device solutions.
- Used consultative sales approach to understand customer needs and recommend relevant offerings.

#### **Education**

2009-04 - **Secondary School Certificate: CBSE** 

2010-06

Kendriya Vidyalaya 3 - Colaba , Mumbai

participate

- Participate in swimming competition
- School and cluster level basketball player.
- $\bullet\;$  Just started to understand the basics of computer.

2011-04 -

#### Higher Secondary Certificate: Science

2012-06

Kendriya Vidyalaya 3 - Colaba, Mumbai

- Participated in various state level cultural programs.
- Avid cyclist.
- Learned Microsoft office and basic HTML in summer.

2012-09 -

# **Bachelor of Engineering: Mechanical**

2017-09

 $Flora\ Institute\ Of\ Technology\ -\ Savitribai\ Phule\ Pune\ University$ 

- Over the course of engineering participated and took initiative for various projects, college events, discussions, voluntary services as both leader and team member.
- Founded Brain-storming club.
- Participated in BAJA racing (National level competition to build and test all-terrain vehicle)
- Leader of suspension design team.
- $\bullet \;\;$  Participated in College website development .
- Member of organizing committee for first ever mech pgcon 2016 pune university
- Participated in ethical Hacking workshop.
- $\bullet \quad Initiated \ / Participated \ in \ Adobe \ Innovator \ CAD/simulation \ workshop.$
- Entry level linux user

# Shubham Singh Bohara

Web Developer

#### **Contact**

Address

Mumbai, MH, 401208

Phone

879 644 6427

E-mail

shubhambohara04@gmail.com

#### Skills

Adobe Innovator-CAD

Progressive web application

Bootstrap

MySQL

JavaScript, HTML, CSS3

PHP

WordPress

LAMP stack admin